const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"While examining the lateral view of the X-ray of the skull, a radiologist points out a region that is the meeting point of the parietomastoid, occipitomastoid, and lambdoid sutures. What point is he referring to?","answers":[{"option":"Asterion","bool":true},{"option":"Inion","bool":false},{"option":"Pterion","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":false},{"option":"Bregma","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"The lymphatic drainage from the palatine tonsil drains into which of the following lymph nodes?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Deep cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Submental","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Jugulodigastric","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"The auditory ossicles articulate through which kind of joint?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrocartilaginous joint","bool":false},{"option":"Synovial joint","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrous joint","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilaginous joint","bool":false},{"option":"Syndesmoses","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following branches of the maxillary artery passes through the foramen spinosum?","answers":[{"option":"Sphenopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Nasopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory meningeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Greater palatine artery","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"The transverse facial artery is a branch of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior auricular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial temporal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Lymph from tongue drain in which of the following lymph nodes?","answers":[{"option":"Deep cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular","bool":false},{"option":"Submental","bool":false},{"option":"Jugulodigastric","bool":false},{"option":"Jugulo-omohyoid","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A young man had a car accident and came to the emergency room (ER) with a fracture of a facial bone that is unpaired. Which bone is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Mandible bone","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary bone","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic bone","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is present in the optic canal?","answers":[{"option":"Ophthalmic artery","bool":true},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"In the case of vitamin A deficiency, keratomalacia occurs. Which of the following characterizes this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Dryness of conjunctiva and cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Unable to see in light or dark condition","bool":false},{"option":"Patient cannot see in low light or in near dark condition","bool":false},{"option":"Localized thickening of conjunctiva","bool":false},{"option":"Dryness and clouding of cornea","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"An oblique facial cleft is a developmental anomaly that occurs due to failure of fusion of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Two maxillary prominence with each other","bool":false},{"option":"Two mandibular prominence with each other","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with medial nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with lateral nasal prominence","bool":true},{"option":"Two medial nasal prominence with each other","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Taste buds are present in the following papillae except:","answers":[{"option":"Filliform","bool":true},{"option":"Fulliform","bool":false},{"option":"Circumvalate","bool":false},{"option":"Foliate","bool":false},{"option":"Fungiform","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which is not present in the carotid sheath?","answers":[{"option":"External jugular vein","bool":true},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Common carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal jugular vein","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"The infraorbital foramen is an opening in which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary bone","bool":true},{"option":"Ethmoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Greater wing of the sphenoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal bone","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following muscles is not supplied by the mandibular nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which muscle takes part in the formation of palatine aponeurosis?","answers":[{"option":"Musculus uvulae","bool":false},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Palatopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Tensor tympani","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A person injures his mandible (ramus) in an accident. Which boundary of the wall of the infratemporal fossa does it form?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior wall","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Aphakia is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudoaphakia","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false},{"option":"Hyphema","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"In lateral view of an X-ray of the head, a physician notices the meeting point of parietooccipital, occipitomastoid, and lambdoid sutures. What is this point called?","answers":[{"option":"Asterion","bool":true},{"option":"Inion","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":false},{"option":"Pterion","bool":false},{"option":"Bregma","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following nerves provide sensory supply to the skin overlying the angle of the mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary branch of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Greater occipital nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A person presents with his right eye looking \"down and out\" with double vision (diplopia) when looking at the right. He has a lesion in which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Right oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Right trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Left trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Left trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Left oculomotor nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"The submandibular lymph nodes are present in which triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Submental triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Omohyoid triangle","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"The suspensory ligaments of the eye are an extension of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Orbital septum","bool":false},{"option":"Tenon's capsule","bool":true},{"option":"Deep fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Periorbital fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial fascia","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A man received a strong blow to the anterior aspect of the mandible during a fight. The tympanic plate of the external auditory meatus was affected. The temporomandibular joint has undergone which type of dislocation?","answers":[{"option":"Superior","bool":false},{"option":"Medial","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A student is studying about a muscle that forms the boundaries of both anterior and posterior triangles. Which of the following is the appropriate muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":true},{"option":"Suprahyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Infrahyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following muscles causes forceful closure of the eyes?","answers":[{"option":"Procerus","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal part of orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Orbital part of orbicularis oculi","bool":true},{"option":"Palpebral part of orbicularis oculi","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which structure does not pass through the superior orbital fissure?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Superior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A girl is facing pre-pubertal acne. The doctor warns her about not squeezing any pimples and prescribes her some special cream for the tip of the nose and the upper lip region acne. What is the most likely reason?","answers":[{"option":"This area requires more special care than the others","bool":false},{"option":"This area is more prone to acne","bool":false},{"option":"This area is richly vascularized","bool":false},{"option":"This area has direct dural venous drainage","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Umami taste fibers are related to?","answers":[{"option":"Organic substances containing nitrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Fructose","bool":false},{"option":"Alkaloids","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":true},{"option":"Acetic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Myopia is corrected by what type of lens?","answers":[{"option":"Convex","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Imaginary","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed","bool":false},{"option":"Concave","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following structures pass through the lateral wall of the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal branches of maxillary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior alveolar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Branches of facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Deep temporal arteries","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following structures forms the anterior wall of the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior surface of maxilla","bool":true},{"option":"Zygomatic arch","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pterygoid plate","bool":false},{"option":"Infratemporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid plate","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which part of the mandible forms the temporomandibular joint?","answers":[{"option":"Coronoid process","bool":false},{"option":"Ramus","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false},{"option":"Condylar process","bool":true},{"option":"Angle","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is not a direct branch of the external carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Ascending pharyngeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual artery","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenopalatine artery","bool":true},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"What is the position of the macula lutea relative to the optic disc in the eyeball?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior","bool":false},{"option":"Superior","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Medial","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Anesthesia in retromolar fossa primarily blocks which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Submandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mental nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior alveolar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following does not take part in the formation of the carotid sheath?","answers":[{"option":"Investing layer of fascia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland sheath","bool":true},{"option":"Prevertebral layer of fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Pretracheal layer of fascia","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Fracture of mandible most likely results in the damage of which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior alveolar nerve","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A nerve winds around the styloid process and carries postganglionic parasympathetic fibers which stimulate salivary secretion in the submandibular and sublingual glands. What is the name of the given nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani","bool":true},{"option":"Deep petrosal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Maxillary sinus drains into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Spheno-ethmoidal recess","bool":false},{"option":"Superior nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle nasal meatus","bool":true},{"option":"Semilunar hiatus","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"The nose has a rich vascular supply. Which of the following arteries does not directly supply the nose?","answers":[{"option":"Sphenopalatine","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior ethmoidal","bool":false},{"option":"Descending palatine","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior ethmoidal","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nasal","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A person feels pain when drinking hot tea. On examination, the central part of the lower lip has an ulcer and associated lymph nodes are swollen. Which nodes are involved?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial cervical lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Deep cervical lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Submental nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Submandibular nodes","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Preganglionic fibers for pupillary reflex reach ciliary ganglion where they synapse and form short ciliary nerves (postganglionic fibers) that innervate the eye. Preganglionic fibers reach ciliary ganglion by which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nasociliary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve to inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Nerve to inferior rectus","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"For near vision, the lens is accommodated to attain increased convexity. Which of the following muscle contracts to help in this action?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Iris","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Dilator pupillae","bool":false},{"option":"Sphincter pupillae","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A 20-year-old boy has an accident. In the accident, the floor of the temporal fossa is fractured. Which of the following structures is not affected?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous part of temporal  bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser wing of sphenoid","bool":true},{"option":"Greater wing of sphenoid","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A person meets an accident and loses all the salivary activity of the submandibular gland. The preganglionic parasympathetic secretomotor fibers to this gland are carried by which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior alveolar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Submental nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Auriculotemporal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A patient has swelling on his face with midface mobility and malocclusion of his teeth with anterior open bite. What kind of fracture is described here/what bone is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Fracture of sphenoid body","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture of nasal bone","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture of zygomatic arch","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillofacial fracture","bool":true}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is true about the common carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"It supplies a branch to the thyroid gland","bool":false},{"option":"It divides into internal and external carotid artery at the upper border of thyroid cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"It has a dilatation on it just after its initiation below the bifurcation","bool":false},{"option":"At the left side, common carotid artery arises from the brachiocephalic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"At the right side, common carotid artery arises from the arch of aorta","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is not a content of the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior alveolar artery","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve to pterygoid canal","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following muscles is attached to the posterior margin of the eyelid?","answers":[{"option":"Levator palpebrae superioris","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial rectus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Orbicularis oculi","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following will not be affected by damage to the superior salivatory nucleus in the pons and facial nerve nucleus lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Stapedius","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":true},{"option":"Occipito-frontalis","bool":false},{"option":"Taste sensation from anterior two thirds","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Damage to the right optic tract causes a defect in which field of vision?","answers":[{"option":"Ipsilateral temporal and contralateral nasal fields","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral nasal and contralateral temporal fields","bool":true},{"option":"Ipsilateral nasal and ipsilateral temporal fields","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral nasal and contralateral temporal fields","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Damage to the right optic nerve will lead to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Total blindness in left eye","bool":false},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Left homonymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Right homonymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Total blindness in right eye","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A patient suffers damage to the orbit resulting in damage to the third cranial nerve. Which of the following signs will be present?","answers":[{"option":"Pupillary constriction and adduction of eye","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary dilatation and abduction of eye","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary constriction and abduction of eye","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary dilatation and adduction of eye","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"The patient is having diplopia with restricted movements of the eye whenever he depresses or adducts the eye. Which nerve is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Sixth","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth","bool":false},{"option":"Third","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following diseases is caused by the deficiency of vitamin A?","answers":[{"option":"Megaloblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Exophthalmos","bool":false},{"option":"Xerophthalmia","bool":true},{"option":"Hair loss","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Cochlear implants are used as a treatment for which type of deafness?","answers":[{"option":"Conductive deafness","bool":false},{"option":"Sensorineural loss","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibulocochlear nerve lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Otosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A hearing aid is most useful in which of the following hearing problems?","answers":[{"option":"Perceptive deafness","bool":false},{"option":"Noise-mediated hearing loss","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":false},{"option":"Sensorineural loss","bool":true},{"option":"Conductive deafness","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"The greatest difference of refractive indices is found at which of the following sites?","answers":[{"option":"Between aqueous humor and the anterior surface of lens","bool":false},{"option":"Between air and anterior surface of cornea","bool":true},{"option":"Between the posterior surface of lens and vitreous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Between posterior surface of cornea and aqueous humor","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Vibrations in the cochlear fluid cause vibration in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Basilar membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Cupula","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Tectorial membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Otolithic membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A patient has sensorineural deafness in the right ear. A 'tuning fork' test will indicate which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Negative Rinne's test in left ear","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Positive Rinne's test in right ear","bool":false},{"option":"Weber's lateralized to right ear","bool":false},{"option":"Weber's lateralized to left ear","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A patient has conductive deafness in the left ear. Which of the following findings will help us know this?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Weber's lateralized to right ear","bool":false},{"option":"Positive Rinne's test in right ear","bool":false},{"option":"Positive Rinne's test in left ear","bool":false},{"option":"Weber's lateralized to left ear","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A person can not listen to low pitch sounds. Which of the following regions is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Round window","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Oval window","bool":false},{"option":"Helicotrema","bool":true},{"option":"Cochlear base","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A person takes aspirin for chest pain. He feels a very strong bitter taste. Which nerve is responsible for carrying taste sensation from the anterior two-thirds of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most sensitive part of the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Macula","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Fovea","bool":true},{"option":"Retina","bool":false},{"option":"Choroid","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A patient comes to the outpatient department with complaints of dryness of nose and palate. Which ganglion must be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Nodose ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Submandibular ganglion","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which type of gland is the gland of Zeis?","answers":[{"option":"Modified sweat glands","bool":false},{"option":"Mucus glands","bool":false},{"option":"Modified sebaceous glands","bool":true},{"option":"Mebomian glands","bool":false},{"option":"Modified lacrimal glands","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which part of the eye continues to grow throughout the lifetime?","answers":[{"option":"Retina","bool":false},{"option":"Lens","bool":true},{"option":"Iris","bool":false},{"option":"Choroid","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Optic vesicles are out pocketings formed by which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Prosencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"The intermaxillary segment is formed by fusion of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary and nasal prominences","bool":false},{"option":"Medial and lateral nasal prominences","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Two lateral nasal prominences","bool":false},{"option":"Two medial nasal prominences","bool":true}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following structures is derived from the 1st pharyngeal arch?","answers":[{"option":"Greater cornu of hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Stylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Malleus","bool":true}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"An infant has a cleft on the right side of the palate behind the incisive foramen. The surgeon identifies it as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bilateral cleft of primary palate","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral cleft of primary and posterior palate","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral cleft of primary palate","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral cleft of secondary palate","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral cleft of posterior (secondary) palate","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is the area of epistaxis in the nose?","answers":[{"option":"Entire nasal septum","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Little's area","bool":true},{"option":"Roof of nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall of nasal cavity","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following structures divides the posterior triangle of the neck into two parts?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior belly of digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Superior belly of omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior belly of digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior belly of omohyoid","bool":true},{"option":"Greater cornu of hyoid bone","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following structures forms the superior border of the digastric triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior belly of omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior belly of digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":false},{"option":"Mandible","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following structures is involved in forming the lateral border of the muscular triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior belly of omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Midline of the neck","bool":false},{"option":"Mandible","bool":false},{"option":"Superior belly of omohyoid","bool":true}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following muscles is involved in shrugging of shoulders?","answers":[{"option":"Deltoid","bool":false},{"option":"Teres major/minor","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis major/minor","bool":false},{"option":"Supraspinatus","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A chef adds too much salt to the soup by mistake. Which of the following is the appropriate area of the tongue which detects salty taste?","answers":[{"option":"Almost entire area of tongue ventrally","bool":false},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior U-shaped area of the tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A person eats something, which is so bitter that he has to puke it out. Which of the following is the appropriate area of the tongue which detects bitter taste?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior U-shaped area of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Almost entire area of tongue ventrally","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A person eats something and finds it to have a delicious taste called umami. Which of the following is the appropriate area of the tongue which detects umami taste?","answers":[{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Almost entire area of tongue ventrally","bool":true},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior U-shaped area of the tongue","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A man plans to lose weight so he cuts off calories and makes a salad for himself. Upon tasting it, he finds out that there is too much lemon in it. Which of the following is the appropriate area of the tongue which detects sour taste?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior U-shaped area of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Almost entire area of tongue ventrally","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A person eats something which is very sweet. Which of the following is the appropriate area of the tongue which detects sweet taste?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior U-shaped area of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Almost entire area of tongue ventrally","bool":false},{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the tympanic membrane?","answers":[{"option":"It consists of 2 layers","bool":false},{"option":"Footplate of stapes attaches to it","bool":false},{"option":"Malleus and incus are derived from first pharyngeal arch during embryogenesis","bool":true},{"option":"Pars flaccida is the area between the umbo of malleus and the posterior malleolar fold","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding mastoid air cells and mastoid antrum?","answers":[{"option":"Suprameatal triangle is antero-inferior to the mastoid process","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoid air cells or antrum opens on the posterior wall of external ear","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoid antrum is separated from middle cranial fossa by tegmen tympani","bool":true},{"option":"The canal for facial nerve is below the aditus to the mastoid antrum","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A friend tells you a person's number. After a few minutes, you can not recall it. This is because it has been wiped out from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Implicit memory","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Short-term memory","bool":true},{"option":"Long-term memory","bool":false},{"option":"Episodic memory","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is true about the canal of Schlemm?","answers":[{"option":"It contains red cells","bool":false},{"option":"It is lined by endothelium","bool":true},{"option":"It communicates with the vitreous chamber","bool":false},{"option":"It is lined by stratified squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"11-cis retinal bound to a specific protein is classified as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Visual pigment","bool":true},{"option":"Retinoid acid binding protein","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Photo-transducer","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediates","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A 45-year-old male is diagnosed with a brain tumor that is pressing on the nerve that passes through a groove between pyramids and olives. Which of the following functions would be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Taste on the ipsilateral side of the anterior two thirds of a tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Paralysis of all the extrinsic muscles of the tongue only","bool":false},{"option":"Taste on the ipsilateral side of the posterior one third of a tongue","bool":false},{"option":"General sensations on the ipsilateral side of the anterior two thirds of a tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Paralysis of all the intrinsic muscles of the tongue","bool":true}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following carries a sense of temperature directly from the anterior two-thirds of a tongue to the thalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Ventro postero lateral nucleus of thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Main sensory nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Motor nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following cells of the brain detect pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Osmoreceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A physician found an infection involving carotid sheath. Which of the following structures might be involved?","answers":[{"option":"Ansa cervicalis","bool":false},{"option":"Common carotid artery","bool":true},{"option":"Sympathetic chain","bool":false},{"option":"External jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following sets of bones have a major contribution to the nasal septum?","answers":[{"option":"Lacrimal and sphenoidal bones","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal cartilage and nasal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Vomer and perpendicular plate of ethmoid","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior and superior nasal conchae","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary and palatine bone","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following types of secretions are released into the troughs of circumvallate papillae?","answers":[{"option":"Entirely mucous from gustatory glands","bool":false},{"option":"Predominantly mucous from parotid gland","bool":false},{"option":"Entirely serous from Von Ebner's gland","bool":true},{"option":"Seromucous","bool":false},{"option":"Predominantly serous from parotid gland","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following structures gives rise to the air-filled cavity present in the petrous part of the temporal bone?","answers":[{"option":"First pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Third pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Second pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"First pharyngeal pouch","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A 10-year-old boy came to the emergency department with a laceration on the tip of the chin which is bleeding. Which of the following arteries must be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Infraorbital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Mental artery","bool":true},{"option":"Buccal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse facial artery","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following lies posterior to the maxilla, inferior and deep to the zygomatic arch and ramus of the mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Middle cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid groove","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Infratemporal fossa","bool":true}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"From which view can pterygopalatine fossa be seen best?","answers":[{"option":"Norma frontalis","bool":false},{"option":"Norma occipitais","bool":false},{"option":"Norma lateralis","bool":true},{"option":"Norma basalis","bool":false},{"option":"Norma verticalis","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Xeropthalmia is defined as dryness of the eye. Damage to which of the following structures can cause xeropthalmia?","answers":[{"option":"Superior cervical ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Ciliary ganglion","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following gives rise to the pigment epithelium layer of an eye?","answers":[{"option":"Pars iris","bool":false},{"option":"Outer layer of optic cup","bool":true},{"option":"Inner layer of optic cup","bool":false},{"option":"Pars ceca retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars ciliaris retinae","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following muscles would be affected in case the trochlear nerve gets damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior oblique muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Medial rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior oblique muscle","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following structures does not pass through the internal acoustic meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibular division of 8th cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Cochlear division of 8th cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Labyrinthine artery","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which muscle must be affected if the upper eye lid is droopy (ptosis)?","answers":[{"option":"Orbital part of orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Palpebral part of orbicularis oculi","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior tarsus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Ethmoidal bulla can be seen in the middle nasal meatus. Which of the following is related to ethmoidal bulla?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ethmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle ethmoidal sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior ethmoidal sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Damage to which of the following structures can cause relative afferent pupillary defect (RAPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Occulomoter nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial temporal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducent nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which type of secretion is produced by the glands at the tip of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"Purely mucous","bool":false},{"option":"gel like secretions","bool":false},{"option":"Purely serous","bool":false},{"option":"Watery secretions","bool":false},{"option":"Seromucous","bool":true}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Why is the temporomandibular joint, a compound condylar variety, called an atypical synovial joint?","answers":[{"option":"It is between temporal bone and mandible","bool":false},{"option":"It is highly moveable joint","bool":false},{"option":"Fibers of lateral pterygoid is are attached directly to the articular capsule","bool":false},{"option":"The articular surface is covered by fibrocartilage","bool":true},{"option":"It is a highly moveable joint but has no synovial fluid","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Light can not pass from which of the following layers of the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Aqueous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Sclera","bool":true},{"option":"Vitreous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Lens","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following muscles would not be affected if the pharyngeal plexus, which lies deep to the middle constrictor gets damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Superior constrictor","bool":false},{"option":"Salpingopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Palatopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Stylopharyngeus","bool":true},{"option":"Middle constrictor","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following terms is defined as the inability to see in the bright light?","answers":[{"option":"Heteropia","bool":false},{"option":"Retinitis pigmentosa","bool":false},{"option":"Xerophthalmia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiplegia retinitis","bool":false},{"option":"Hemeralopia","bool":true}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Maximal movement is shown by which of the following joints when the head moves horizontally such as to say \"no\"?","answers":[{"option":"C8-T1","bool":false},{"option":"Atlanto-occipital","bool":false},{"option":"C2-C3","bool":false},{"option":"C3-C4","bool":false},{"option":"Atlanto axial","bool":true}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A 7-year-old presents to the outpatient department with the complaint of difficulty in chewing and swallowing. He also complains of pain in the auricular region and external ear. After examination, the doctor finds that there is an inflammation of the parotid gland. Which of the following nerves must be irritated to cause this pain?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Auriculotemporal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is an active metabolite of vitamin A present in the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Retinal","bool":true},{"option":"Beta carotene","bool":false},{"option":"Carotenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Dorsum of the tongue is lined by which epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous non-keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous partially keratinized","bool":true}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following are the end products of hydrolysis of retinyl esters in intestinal mucosa?","answers":[{"option":"Retinal and retinol","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoic acid and free fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal and free fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoic acid and retinol","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol and free fatty acids","bool":true}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following muscles is attached to the articular disc of the temporomandibular joint?","answers":[{"option":"Medial pterygoid muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Massetor","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following muscles are involved in the formation of transverse and vertical wrinkles on the forehead?","answers":[{"option":"Corrugator supercilii and orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Frontalis and mentalis","bool":false},{"option":"Frontalis and orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Corrugator supercilii and mentalis","bool":false},{"option":"Frontalis and corrugator supercilii","bool":true}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following contains receptors to detect centrifugal acceleration in order to determine angular acceleration?","answers":[{"option":"Cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibule","bool":false},{"option":"Saccule","bool":false},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false},{"option":"Semicircular canals","bool":true}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which wall of the middle ear contains an opening for the pharyngotympanic tube?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"Roof","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior wall","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following triangles of neck contains chemoreceptors?","answers":[{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Mental triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Submental triangle","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Third-order neurons of the taste pathway terminate at which of the following areas of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Broadman's area 6","bool":false},{"option":"Broadman's area 22","bool":false},{"option":"Broca's area","bool":false},{"option":"Opercular insular area","bool":true},{"option":"Broadman's area 17","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A soldier lost his sense of hearing due to exposure to loud sounds. Damage to which of the following organs can result in hearing loss?","answers":[{"option":"Cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Inner hair cells","bool":true},{"option":"Saccule","bool":false},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibule","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following suprahyoid muscles is supplied by C1 fibers along the hypoglossal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Stylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Geniohyoid","bool":true},{"option":"Stylothyroid","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following nerves does not pass through the jugular foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal part of accessory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve to stylopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial part of accessory nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is correct about the nerve that is responsible for the physiological peristaltic movements of the gastrointestinal tract?","answers":[{"option":"Originates from pons","bool":false},{"option":"Does not give cardiac branches in the neck","bool":false},{"option":"Exits skull through foramen magnum","bool":false},{"option":"Present outside the carotid sheath","bool":false},{"option":"Joined by cranial part of accessory nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following regions has the most abundant distribution of fungiform papillae?","answers":[{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsum of tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior 2/3rd of a tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":true}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the cause of the coloboma?","answers":[{"option":"Abnormal development of optic cup","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of optic cup to close","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of lens vesicle to close","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of choroidal fissure to close","bool":true},{"option":"Failure of separation of eyelids","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the function of the myenteric plexus in causing the peristaltic movements of the gut?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibiting circular muscle below the bolus","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulating circular muscles above the bolus","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibiting longitudinal muscles below the bolus","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibiting vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibiting circular muscle above the bolus","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the anterior aspect of the external auditory meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Auriculotemporal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following structures is damaged if norma lateralis is fractured and cranial nerve VII is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Stapedius","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor tympani","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Nasolacrimal duct drains tears to which of the following parts of the nose?","answers":[{"option":"Lacrimal sac","bool":false},{"option":"Superior nasal conchae","bool":false},{"option":"Superior nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior nasal meatus","bool":true}]},{"id":129,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is responsible for the detection of the direction from which the sound is coming?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezoid body","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral superior olivary nucleus","bool":true}]},{"id":130,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Parasympathetic fibers arising from which of the following are responsible for the constriction of a pupil and making a lens more convex?","answers":[{"option":"Ciliary ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cervical ganglion","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Nucleus ambigous does not give fibers to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve to stylopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Constrictor muscles of pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Superior two-thirds of esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Intrinsic muscles of larynx","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A person comes to the clinic with complaints of drooping of the right upper eyelid and inability to keep his right eye open. Which of the following muscles is most likely involved?","answers":[{"option":"Orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Levator palpebrae superioris","bool":true}]},{"id":133,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following are found abundantly in the fovea?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cones","bool":true},{"option":"Rods","bool":false},{"option":"Oxyntic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"A few students while conducting research found that some areas of the tongue are stimulated when they get in touch with ionized molecules. Which of the following taste sensations will be produced by these ionized molecules?","answers":[{"option":"Salty and umami","bool":false},{"option":"Salty and sweet","bool":false},{"option":"Bitter and sweet","bool":false},{"option":"Sweet and umami","bool":false},{"option":"Salty and sour","bool":true}]},{"id":135,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is a voluntary phase of swallowing?","answers":[{"option":"Intestinal phase","bool":false},{"option":"Saliva secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Oral phase","bool":true},{"option":"Pharyngeal phase","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal phase","bool":false}]},{"id":136,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most important process in swallowing that prevents the entry of food into the larynx?","answers":[{"option":"Upward movement of uvula","bool":false},{"option":"Closure of vocal cords","bool":false},{"option":"Forward movement of larynx","bool":true},{"option":"Upward movement of pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of epiglottis","bool":false}]}]
export default arr